Contact

chauchau120120@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/danylo-bilous-b4a72b312 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence

HTML / CSS / JavaScript / TypeScript

React / Redux / Next / React Native

Material UI / Tailwind CSS

Python / Django

Angular / AngularJS

Node / Express

C# / ASP.NET

PHP / Vue / Laravel

AWS / Azure / Docker

Git / GitHub / GitLab /Bitbucket

Team Leadership

Team Management

Team Motivate

Teamwork

Agile Methodologies

Daily Report

Daily Scrum

MySQL/PostgreSQL/MongDB/SQLite

WordPress / Shopify

Danylo Bilous

Proven and Experienced Full Stack Engineer | Team Leader | DevOps | Al

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

Summary

Senior Full Stack Engineer with 8+ years of experience designing, developing, maintaining web & mobile services and apps. Excellent ability to meet deadlines and work as part of a team to deliver great work. High proficiency in object-oriented methodologies, data structures, and algorithms, as well as quality coding and excellent debugging skills. Since I'm a cool-hearted person, so usually see every difficulty with a positive side and keep myself always smiling which makes me stronger even. Proven track record in optimizing application performance, reducing bugs, and improving overall code quality, resulting in increased user engagement and revenue growth.

Experience

Upwork

Principal Full Stack Engineer May 2024 - Present (2 months)

San Francisco, California, United States

inVesti Financial

Senior Frontend & DevOps Engineer

January 2024 - April 2024 (4 months)

Arlington, Texas, United States

- ✓ Managed and developed whole frontend side using React/Redux/MUI from Figma with pixel-perfect.
- ✓ Worked with COO and CEO directly to get requirements to implement financial logics.
- ✓ Worked as DevOps Engineer to host React / MUI / TypeScript frontend and Django backend using AWS and GoDaddy.
- ✓ Managed source using Git/GitHub.
- ✓ Fixed and maintenance backend Structure, database Model and logic

Phantom Network

Principal Skilled Full Stack Engineer | Team leader

September 2021 - December 2023 (2 years 4 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- ✓ Supervised a team of 7 developers to develop the ecommerce websites to increase 20% revenue using Python, Django, React and TypeScript.
- ✓ Boosted system performance by optimizing database queries and reducing server response time. reducing bounce rate by 5.5%.
- ✓ Developed 2 websites with outstanding content. Layout, and functionalities using C#/ASP.NET and Angular.
- ✓ Designed, developed, and maintained multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages, reaching over 250,000 users, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript frameworks such as React/Node/TypeScript and Python/ Django.
- ✓ Built a web application MVP for a dropship management platform with 75+ business customers to create manage and monitor deliveries using Node, and Python. Ethers for integrating Ethereum.
- ✓ Developed 1 decentralized social media web application using React, CSS, Bootstrap and web3,js.
- ✓ Devised an Ethereum smart contracts and MVP that allowed over 3.9K developers to sell software licenses using 17 embeddable widgets.
- ✓ Involved in full life cycle of the project from requirements gathering, analyzing, designing UI/data base using agile scrum methodology.

Node Audio Ltd Senior Full Stack Engineer March 2019 - July 2021 (2 years 5 months) City Of Bristol, England, United Kingdom

- ✓ Managed team of 7+ members and monitored projects to ensure progress
- ✓ Increase revenue by 10% over the course of 2 years.
- ✓ Led design, and development of 30+ new features using NextJS/TypeScript /Tailwind CSS.
- ✓ Developed 3+ applications following Agile software methodologies using Angular/C#/ASP.NET, Python/Django, and AWS.
- ✓ Collaborated with 2 different development cross-functional teams on 4 new projects designs and feature improvement.
- ✓ Delivered outstanding UX for 50,000+ customers, driving the usability, look, and feel of both mobile and iOS app to achieve 300+ new 5-star ratings using React Native and XCode.

Fleamint

Mid - Senior Full Stack Developer February 2016 - April 2018 (2 years 3 months)

Singapore, Singapore

- ✓ Designed and configured database and backend applications and programs, contributing to operations continuity and increasing efficiency by 14%.
- ✓ Worked on the improvement of data protection and security, increasing the security rate by 24% while creating new user information solutions.
- ✓ Launched 2 original e-commerce website and web applications, encompassing design, coding, testing, and maintenance with a team of 5 web developers.
- ✓ Coordinated with the engineering team of 35 to discuss user interface ideas and application.

Education

University of Southern California
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (April 2009 - May 2014)